discovermodus.com 2015-03-24

# Privacy Policy - Modus

### At MODUS, we respect and are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy lets you know how your personal information is processed and used. We promise that we will take steps to use your personal information only in ways that are compatible with this Privacy Policy.

### About the Safe Harbor Program

Modus complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Modus has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Modus’ certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

The “Safe Harbor” program was jointly established in June 2000 by the United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission, as a method for transferring personal information from the European Union (EU), to companies in the United States. The program is a voluntary self-certification process for companies operating in the United States. Companies that certify represent that they are upholding privacy standards for personal information received from the EU that have been jointly accepted by the EU Commission and the US Department of Commerce. These standards exceed current US privacy standards.

“Personal Information” means information that can directly or indirectly lead to the identification of a living person, such as an individual’s name, address, e-mail, telephone number, license number, medical identification number, photograph, or other identifying characteristic. The identification can occur by reference to one or more factors specific to the individual’s physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. Personal information does not include information that has been anonymized, encoded or otherwise stripped of its identifiers, or information that is publicly available, unless combined with other non-public personal information.

### Notice and Choice

MODUS collects personally identifying information as part of the Terms of Service of using our services. This information includes such things as name, physical address, phone number, email address and other information for billing purposes. This information is used primarily for billing and contact purposes as it relates to the use of our products.We also receive and store any information you enter on our website or give us in any other way. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of some of our features or offers. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, improving our Website, and communicating with you. MODUS will NEVER sell any information that we have collected, personally identifying or otherwise, to a third party. This information is deemed proprietary information of MODUS and will only be used by our staff.

### Consumer Opt-Out / Inscribe

To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail campaign from us (if your computer supports such capabilities). If you do not want to receive e-mail from us, please reply to any e-mail you receive from us by requesting to be “unsubscribed,” or by simply clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any e-mail campaign you receive from us.

### Transfers

MODUS will not disclose an individual’s personal information to third parties unless directed by our client or when one or more of the following conditions are true:

We have the individual’s permission to make the disclosure;  
The disclosure is required by law or professional standards;  
The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or disposition of all  
or part of our business;  
The information in question is publicly available;  
The disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or  
defense of legal claims  
Data Security

MODUS takes our clients security seriously and undertakes every reasonable step to protect their information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use and confidentiality of information, either for its own purposes or on behalf of our clients, MODUS has put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we process.

### Data Integrity

MODUS uses personal information only in a manner that is compatible with the purpose for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. MODUS takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete and current.

### Access and Correction

MODUS processes data under the guidance and direction of our clients. Upon request, MODUS will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that it maintains about them. In addition, MODUS will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, change, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. Enforcement, Complaints, and Questions MODUS participates in the Safe Harbor program developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Union. MODUS has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles agreed upon by the U.S. and the E.U. You may visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Safe Harbor web site for more information about the Safe Harbor.

If you have a question or complaint regarding MODUS privacy policy or MODUS use of personal information, you may contact MODUS through this web site or by writing us at the following address:

MODUS  
ATTN: Safe Harbor Inquiries  
2001 S Street NW  
Suite 710  
Washington, DC 20009

If for some reason you do not receive acknowledgment of your complaint or your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by MODUS, you should then contact:

Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.  

If an individual files such a complaint, MODUS will investigate the matter and attempt to resolve all issues to the satisfaction of the complainant. If the matter cannot be settled, MODUS agrees to cooperate with the dispute resolution system set forth above.
